&gt；&gt；steve：让我们玩一些其他的东西。
&gt;&gt; Steve: Let's play
with some other stuff.
&GT；&GT；史蒂夫：我会做所有这些，我会再打一次电话。
&gt;&gt; Steve: I'm gonna do all those,
and I'm gonna call one more time.
&gt；&gt；steve：因为像这样的东西可以做各种各样的事情，对吗？
&gt;&gt; Steve: Because like this thing
can do all sorts of things, right?
加号是通用的。
The plus sign is versatile.
我可以将数字相加并将其植入字符串。
I can add numbers and plant it in strings.
这是JavaScript中最好的函数。
This is the best function in JavaScript.
我们会去做的，我们会这样做的。
We'll go ahead and we'll do that.
&gt；&gt；steve：好的，它被优化了，但我觉得这不是全部。
&gt;&gt; Steve: All right, it was optimized, but
I feel like that wasn't the full story.
对，会发生什么，好吧，
Right, what would happen, all right,
让我做另一面旗帜，这是我们可以一起玩的地方。
let me do another flag and
this is where we can all play together.
有人想猜猜Trace deopt是做什么的吗？
Anyone wanna guess what trace deopt does?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：否。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No.
&gt；&gt；[笑]。
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH].
&GT；&GT；史蒂夫：在某一点上，你们都喜欢，这就是我们都关注的方式。
&gt;&gt; Steve: At one point you are all like,
this is how we all pay attention.
在某一点上，我将输入TRACE DEOPT或DEPOT。
At one point I am going to type
in like trace deopt, or depot.
因为我已经做过1000次了，
Because I have done it 1,000 times,
我没有理由不在很多人面前做这件事。
there is no reason I wouldn't do
it in front of a lot of people.
当我看起来很困惑为什么事情没有发生时，必须有人打电话给我
Someone has to call me on that one when
I look confused as to why things didn't
工作，好的。
work, okay.
酷，让我们运行它。
Cool, let's run that.
&gt；&gt；steve：这里有一大堆东西。
&gt;&gt; Steve: There's a bunch of stuff here.
去优化函数，有趣。
Deoptimizing the function, interesting.
所以它进行了优化，然后取消了优化。
So it optimized and then it deoptimized.
如果我去掉这条线呢？
What if I take out this line?
它只是优化了。
It only optimized.
我想我们已经准备好做一个假设了。
I think we are ready to make a hypothesis.
顺便说一下我们在做科学。
We're doing science by the way.
酷，所以我们加了两个数字很多次。
Cool, so
we added two numbers a bunch of times.
然后我们添加了两个字符串，这让我们去优化了。
And then we added two strings and
that got us deoptimized.
有人想要一个风险假设吗？
Anyone want a venture hypothesis?
如果没有我有幻灯片不用担心，没有压力。
If not I have slides don't worry,
no pressure.
我只是要为假设敞开大门。
I'm just gonna open the floor for
hypothesis.
有人有吗？
Anyone got one?
好吧，精神上，至少我们有怀疑。
All right, mentally,
like we have suspicions at least.
可能还没准备好。
May not be ready.
我看到人们，他们已经把手举起来，但他们还没有完全准备好。
I see people they've got their hands up
the mouth up but they're not fully ready.
没有错误的答案。
There's no wrong answers.
我的意思是，有错误的答案，因为这是一个算法，这里有科学。
I mean, there are wrong answers cuz this
is an algorithm, there's science here.
但我们是朋友，对吧？
But we're amongst friends, right?
聊天室和这里。
Both chat room and here.
酷，所以我们有一些
Cool, so we have some
假设，非常好。
hypotheses, very nice.
是的，对于那些你在聊天中的人，我看到了问题。
Yeah, for those you're in the chat,
I see the question.
我有一张幻灯片，会很好的。
I got a slide, it's going to be good.
好的，我们看到我们从中得到的两个不同的东西
All right, so we see that the two
different things we're getting out of
去优化不清楚这里发生了什么。
de-optimization unclear
what's happening here.
好的，所以这是一个问题，所以发生了什么，让我们尝试其他的东西。
All right, so that's a problem, so
what happens, let's try something else up.
我要做两次。
I'm gonna do it twice.
&GT；&GT；史蒂夫：我们现在不需要这条线，
&gt;&gt; Steve: We don't need
this line right now,
我们知道这条线是有问题的。
we know that that line is problematic.
我们会继续下去，没有基准。
And we'll go ahead, and no benchmark.
我们现在不要对追踪行动做任何事。
Let's not do anything with
the trace ops right now.
&GT；&GT；史蒂夫：这将需要更长的时间，因为它是，我们正在做两次。
&gt;&gt; Steve: It will take a little longer
cuz it's, we're doing it twice.
令人怀疑的是需要更长的时间。
It's taking suspiciously longer.
&gt；&gt；Steve：我要回去看看这里发生了什么。
&gt;&gt; Steve: I'm gonna go back over and
see what's going on here.
&gt；&gt；steve：我们必须设置。
&gt;&gt; Steve: We have to set.
&gt；&gt；Steve：我们将重新设置迭代。
&gt;&gt; Steve: We'll set
the iterations back up.
&gt；&gt；steve：酷，拍了47张，只是，精神笔记。
&gt;&gt; Steve: Cool, took 47,
just, mental note.
47毫秒
47 milliseconds.
让我们把那条有问题的线放回去。
Let's put that problematic line back in.
好的，差不多，不是双倍，几乎是时间的两倍，对吧？
Okay, almost, not double,
almost double the amount of time, right?
所以即使在中间的某个地方，我们也可以看到，就像有不同的类型
So even somewhere in the middle there we
can see that like having different types
的参数肯定超过了那个函数，
of arguments past that
function definitely,
那里肯定有问题。
there's definitely a problem there.
它肯定引起了某种减速，对吧？
It definitely caused some
kind of slow down, right?
以后再谈这个。
Talk more about this later.
我们现在只是在做心理笔记。
We're just taking mental notes right now.
我们在做科学研究。
We're doing science.
我们在金科玉律下填满我们的实验笔记本
We're filling up our lab notebooks
underneath the golden rules and
我们稍后会做一些测试，酷。
we'll make some test later, cool.
好吧，那绝对，绝对是个问题。
All right, that was definitely,
definitely a problem.
让我们再运行一次代码。
Let's also run the code one more time.
我们要做的另一个节点技巧是，我们将继续
We're gonna do another little
node trick is, we'll go ahead and
我们将使用一些你以前可能没有见过，也许有过的语法。
we're gonna use some syntax you
might not seen before, maybe have.
假设NeverOptimizeFunction(Add)。
It's let's say NeverOptimizeFunction(add).
你喜欢，我为什么要用这个？
Your like, why would I ever use this?
好消息是你不能，这不是真的，
Good news is that you can't,
it's It's not real, it's kind of real,
但这不是真的。
but it's not really real.
所以我们会说节点，我们会说这允许本机语法，
So we'll say node and
we'll say this allow natives syntax,
这基本上是为了调试。
which is basically this is for debugging.
这使您可以将某些标志解析为V8，该标志将继续并
This lets you parse certain flags
to V8 that will go ahead and
让你进一步喜欢调试信息。
get you further like
debugging information.
所以在这里我们想要做的是，我们有效地，
So here what we wanna do is,
we effectively,
我们将使用这个，你看到它的前缀是一个百分号，对吧？
we're gonna use this, you saw it was
prefixed with a percent sign, right?
这是因为这不是有效的JavaScript，它将在启用此标志的情况下工作，
This is cuz that's not valid JavaScript,
that will work with this flag on,
代码不会在没有标志的情况下运行，这基本上是一种触发东西的方式，所以
the code will not run without the flag on,
it's basically a way to trigger stuff so
你可以看到效果。
you can kind of see the effects.
所以我们继续说，
So we'll go ahead, say that,
我将调用Benchmark 235毫秒。
I'll call benchmark 235 milliseconds.
我们之前在41岁时运行过两次，对吗？
We ran it twice before at 41, right?
显然，这种优化是有用的，我们应该完全保留它。
Clearly, that optimization is useful and
we should totally keep it.
是的，如果我们从不优化函数，它肯定会慢很多。
Yeah, if we never optimize the function,
it is definitely way slower.
所以我们知道这里发生了一些事情，即使当我
So we know that there are some
things happening here even when I
去过一次优化。
got deoptimized once.
好像又热起来了。
It seems like got reheated back up.
我们可以看到，不优化它从来都不是一件伟大的事情。
We can see that non optimizing
it ever is not a great thing.
这样也就像是推销。
And like that is also like a sales pitch.
就像这是一个简单的添加功能。
Like this is a simple add function.
你可以想象有多复杂的函数。
You can imagine what a much
more complicated function.
如果我们能优化这些。
If we can optimize those.
您可以看到高达100倍的性能。
You can see up to 100 X more performance.
酷毙了。
Cool.
让我们看得更深一点。
Let's look a little bit deeper.
我们现在实际上要转到另一个文件，这个文件名为add。
We're actually going to go to a different
file now, this one that's called add.
你看这里我们有一个函数。
And you see here we have a function.
我们将在这里使用另一种特殊的本机语法，称为Optimize function on
We're going to use another special native
syntax here called optimize function on
下一个电话。
next call.
有人想大胆猜猜这个函数是做什么的吗？
Anyone want to take a wild
guess what this function does?
免费的。
For the freebie.
[笑]某人[笑]
[LAUGH] Someone [LAUGH].
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：它不会优化下一个Fuinciton？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: It doesn't
optimise the next fuinciton?
&gt；&gt；steve：那么下一个函数上的下一个函数呢？
&gt;&gt; Steve: Well the next
function on the next function?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：是的。史蒂夫：是的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Steve: Yeah.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：第二个呼叫。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: The second call.
&gt；&gt；steve：好吧，下一次
&gt;&gt; Steve: Well on the next
打电话。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：好的。
call.
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Okay.
&gt；&gt；steve：对。
&gt;&gt; Steve: Right.
此时将对其进行优化。
It will be optimize at that point.
现在我们需要在某一点上允许我
Now we need that allow At one point I'll
也忘了给原住民复数，所以
forget to pluralize natives as well, so
负责这件事的人。曾经和
somebody who's in charge of that one.
Had and
也会，让我们扔
will also,let's throw
在跟踪选项中。酷，我们可以看到它是优化的。
in the trace opt.
Cool, we can see that it was optimized.
即使我们只运行了一次，这也是有意义的。
Which makes sense even
though we only ran it once.
就像函数通常在第一次运行时没有被优化一样，
Like a function usually is not
optimized the first time it is run,
因为去优化室不是免费的。
because going to the optimizing
parlor isn't free.
对吧？
Right?
那里有工作发生。
There's work that happens there.
当我们工作的时候会发生什么？
And what happens when we do work?
这需要一些时间。
It takes some time.
对吧？所以我们希望如果我们要
Right?
So we hope that if we're going to
通过将其发送到优化客厅来完成工作，它会走得更快。
do work by sending it to
the optimizing parlor, it goes faster.
然后如果我们把它变成字符串本身会发生什么。
And then what happens if we
turn this into a string per se.
&gt；&gt；Steve：我们也会跟踪deopt。
&gt;&gt; Steve: We'll also trace deopt.
&gt；&gt；steve：我想我告诉你把事情搞砸了。
&gt;&gt; Steve: I guess i've
ruined it by telling you.
这次我们也会追踪失优化。
We'll also trace
the deoptimizaion this time.
您可以看到，我们在一次调用该函数后就取消了该函数的优化
You can see that we deoptimize that
function just after one time calling it
有一些不同的论点。
with some different arguments.
好吧。
Right.
我们不知道又发生了什么。
We don't know what's happening again.
但我认为我们已经到了准备好的地步，
But I think we are getting to
the point where we are ready to,
就像，想一想这件事。
like, think a little bit about this.
酷毙了。
Cool.
让我们回去谈谈我们刚才看到的。
Let's go back and
talk about what we just saw.
所以这个函数，我们以前见过。
So this function, we've seen it before.
除了这个有语法错误并且不能运行。
Except this one has a syntax error and
won't run.
所以不要看那边。
So don't look at that side.
我们仍然有它去优化编译器。
We still have it went to
the optimizing compiler.
我们有这个更快的版本。
We got this faster version.
一个版本，你知道47毫秒和235之间的区别。
A version that was you know the difference
between 47 milliseconds and 235.
但就像我们看到的那样，正在发生的事情将会发生。
But like that's the stuff that is
happening is going to we saw that.
这是使用我们之前说过的东西，并且
This is using the thing
that we said before, and
有一些要点叫做投机性优化。
there's bullet points called
speculative optimization.
我们使用翻译，因为翻译已经准备好了。
We use the interpreter cuz
the interpreter is ready to go.
但是它不知道关于我们的代码的任何东西，所以它没有Turbofan那么快。
But it doesn't know anything about our
code, so it's not as fast as Turbofan is.
它需要知道的优化编译器。
The optimizing compiler It needs to know.
JavaScript不是类型化语言。
JavaScript is not a typed language.
它不知道它每次都会得到两个数字，对吧。
It doesn't know that it's gonna
get two numbers every time, right.
所以发生的事情就是翻译就像我会处理这件事一样。
So what happens is the interpreter
is like I would handle this.
我会做一堆艰苦的工作。
I would do a bunch of hard work.
我会查清楚一切都会好起来的。
I will look everything up
It's all gonna be fine.
它走在前面，它以缓慢的方式做这件事。
It goes and it gets ahead and
it's doing it the slow way.
最终，就像嘿，它正在生成这些反馈对象
Eventually it's like hey it's generating
these feedback objects that are going
对涡轮风扇来说，我想我已经足够了解人们是怎么称呼它的了
to turbofans like, I think I know enough
about how people are calling this
添加我认为我已经准备好做出决定的函数。
add function that I think that
I'm ready to make the decision.
它总是有两个数字，对吧？
It always gets two numbers, right?
一旦我们对它有了足够的了解，我们就可以假设即使是这片荒无人烟的西部
And once we know enough about it we can
assume that even this untyped wild west of
一种编程语言，是的，没有类型，没有保证，
a programming language That yeah
there's not type, no guarantees,
但我们很确定每次都会通过数字
but we're pretty certain that numbers
are going to get passed in every time and
这就是它成为被优化的候选者的时候。
that's when it becomes a candidate for
being optimized.
如果一根绳子滑进去了呢？
And if a string slips in there?
好吧会发生什么？
All right what happens?
当我[笑]我认为发生的一切都不是真的。
As I [LAUGH] everything I
thought happens isn't true.
对吧？
Right?
所以，在这一点上，我们得到了红色箭头。
So, at that point, we get the red arrow.
对吧？在这一点上就像是，听着，
Right?
And at that point it's like, listen,
我做了所有这些假设，我以为会是数字。
I made all these assumptions,
I thought it was going to be numbers.
我不知道发生了什么
I don't know what's happening any more.
点火你把这个拿回去。
Ignition you take this back.
很明显我处理不了这件事。
I clearly can't handle this.
当我们回到字节码时，对吗？
Which when we go back to the byte code,
right?
优化编译器针对它看到的内容进行优化，但是
The optimizing compiler optimizes for
what it's seen but
如果它看到一些新的有问题的东西，对吧，结果就像
if it sees something new That's
problematic right it turns out that like
有几次它会好的，我已经准备好重新优化，如果这发生得足够多的话
a few times it will alright I'm ready
to re-optimize if that happens enough
因为这样的成本是昂贵的，所以像我这样的去优化编译器是昂贵的
times cuz like that cost is expensive
the de-optimizing compiler which is like I
别再碰这个功能了，明白了吗？
don't touch this function
anymore right you get it?
然后那个数字我现在不会说这个数字因为它改变了但是
Then that number I'm not gonna say the
number right now because it changes but
就像当你在一段时间后变得像Strings一样
like after a certain number of times
of getting like Strings when you were
期望像你这样的数字基本上会在一个像OK Optimize这样的循环中结束
expecting numbers like you would end up in
a basically a loop of like okay optimize
这个函数很酷，它优化了它，好吧，它又变热了，就像优化一样
the function cool it optimizes it alright
it's getting hot again like optimize
函数知道另一个字符串滑进来了，它只会玩那个游戏，所以
the function know another string slipped
in it's only gonna play that game so
很多次对吧？
many times right?
最后，就像我没有优化这个函数，我一直在做这个
And then eventually it's like I don't
optimize this function I've been down this
路我不再感兴趣了，这不再是我的生活。
road I'm not interested anymore
it's not the life I live anymore.
好吧。所以，就像我们的代码有大量的
Right.
So, like if our code has a wild number of
不同的变量，那么它完全有可能放弃。
different variables then it is totally
possible that it just gives up.
酷毙了。
Cool.
所以我们现在知道，我们知道一些关于字符串和数字的知识，对吗？
So we now know, we know a little
about strings and numbers, right?
但显然JavaScript不仅仅是字符串和
But clearly there's more to
JavaScript than strings and
数字，所以我们要跳进去玩更多的代码。
numbers so we're going to jump in and
play around with a little more code.
好吧。我会回答一个问题
All right.
I'll answer one question and
那我们就回去吧
then we'll get back to it.
酷毙了。
Cool.
所以有一个问题，比如一个函数要被调用多少次。
So there was a question of like how
many times a function has to get called.
完全不一定。
That's not necessarily at all.
这取决于有多少次，就像，它不是，改变了。
It depends on how many times,
like, it's not, that changes.
但是，就像，我们不会亲自调用一个函数很多次。
But of the, like, we don't personally
call a function a lot of times.
对吧？
Right?
但我们并不总是，就像我们不写函数并不意味着，
But we don't always, like just cuz we
don't write the function doesn't mean,
就像我们不知道它叫什么，对吧？
like we don't know what it was called,
right?
例如，我们知道在React中渲染方法被称为“Anytime
So for instance, we know in React
that render method is called "Anytime
我们的应用程序中的“State Changes”，对吗？
State Changes" in our application, right?
因此呈现方法可以被调用“Anytime”，特别是如果
So that render method could get
called "anytime", especially if
它在正在传递的应用程序组件中声明。
it's stated in the application
component that's getting passed down.
对，render被调用了，即使我们从未多次编写render。
Right, render's getting called, even if
we never write render more than once.
因此，我们的代码中有些部分最终被调用了很多次，对吗？
So there are parts of our code that
end up getting called a lot, right?
如果你考虑一下我之前展示的我自己的应用程序的火焰图，
If you think about that flame graph that
I showed earlier of my own application,
火焰燃烧得很深，有很多小碎片。
that flame got down and deep and
there were a lot of little pieces.
顶端的部分相当大，但有很多小部分是
The top pieces were pretty big, but there
were a lot of little pieces that were
一次又一次地接到电话，当我去做的时候，我真的很惊讶
getting called repeatedly That I was
actually surprised by when I went to do
调查[INAUDIBLE]有时像我们认为不是的代码
that investigating [INAUDIBLE] so
sometimes like code that we don't think is
与我们的应用程序中的状态更改相比，调用次数很多。
getting called a lot versus state
changes in our application do.
好的，酷。
All right, cool.
因此，让我们看看更多代码重做，
So let's take a look at
some more code redo,
&gt；&gt；[INAUDIBLE]
&gt;&gt; [INAUDIBLE]
&gt；&gt；steve：酷
&gt;&gt; Steve: Cool
&gt；&gt；[INAUDIBLE]
&gt;&gt; [INAUDIBLE]
史蒂夫：是的。
&gt;&gt; Steve: Yeah.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 2：如果您在定义类型时使用类似Flow的东西。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: If you're using something
like flow where you're defining the types.
这是他们优化的东西还是可以像处理和意识到的一样？
Is that's something they optimize or
can like handle and like be aware of or?
史蒂夫：是的。
&gt;&gt; Steve: Yes.
这也是一个类似于最近的问题。
That was also a question like recent.
就像你可以强制执行的任何东西一样。
Like anything where you can enforce.
你总是试图交出相同的类型会有效地加快它的速度
That you're always trying to hand the same
types in will effectively speed up It is
你不太可能最终得到不是那种类型的代码，对吧？
less likely that you'll end up with
code that is not of that type, right?
是的，就像我们用打字稿写的一样，它是经过编译的。
Yeah, like we write in TypeScript,
it get's compiled.
它是JavaScript。
It is JavaScript.
会不会有什么事情发生在它两次落下的地方？
Could something happen
where it gets down twice?
完全正确。
Totally.
是的，使用TypeScript，Flow，ReasonML都将肯定
Yeah, using TypeScript, Flow,
ReasonML will all definitely
就像你在帮助涡轮风扇帮助你在这些点上，对吗？
like You are helping turbo fan
help you at those points, right?
因此，在这些情况下会有潜在的性能提升。
So there are potential
performance gains in those cases.
好的，让我们往前跳一跳，我们将
All right, so let's actually go ahead and
jump back in a little bit, we're gonna
稍微改变一下，这样我们就会失去我们的旧时尚添加功能。
change this a little, so we're gonna
lose our good old fashion add function.
我们可以再写一遍。
We could always write it again.
我相信我对这个代码了如指掌。
I feel confident that I know this
code like the back of my hand.
&gt；&gt；steve：好的，酷。
&gt;&gt; Steve: All right, cool.
所以你可以说&gt；&gt；Steve：让我们创建一个JavaScript类。
So you could say
&gt;&gt; Steve: Let's make a JavaScript class.
&gt；&gt；Steve：他们将取x和y&gt；&gt；Steve：this.y=y。
&gt;&gt; Steve: They'll take x and y
&gt;&gt; Steve: This.y = y.
好的，很酷，我们要继续
All right cool and
we're just gonna go ahead and
我们将JSON一串[INAUDIBLE]很多次。
we're gonna JSON a string of
[INAUDIBLE] a bunch of times.
因此，当有迭代时，我们会说&gt；&gt；Steve：等于新的点。
So while there are iterations we'll say
&gt;&gt; Steve: Equals the new point.
2和4。
2 and 4.
我们可以使用迭代次数。
We could use the iteration number.
我们可以做任何我们想做的事。
We could do whatever we want.
这是密码。
It's code.
&gt；&gt；steve：好的，让我们继续，让我们运行它。
&gt;&gt; Steve: All right let's go ahead and
let's run that.
&GT；&GT；史蒂夫：这真的需要很长的时间。
&gt;&gt; Steve: That's taking
a really long time.
你可以看到它花了大约5秒。
You can see it took about 5 seconds.
如果是那样的话，我想我们已经表达了我们的观点。
In that case I think we've made our point.
让我们用稍微少一点的喜欢来继续。
Let's go ahead with like slightly less.
所以，这是一百万。
So, it's a million.
酷毙了。
Cool.
所以在这里我们可以看到大约半秒到课。
So here we can see about
half a second to class.
而且并不容易。
And is not easy.
那里有很多规则。
There's a lot of rules there.
这不是世界上最简单的事情。
It's not the simplest thing in the world.
&gt；&gt；steve：但是假设我们设置了。
&gt;&gt; Steve: But let's say that we set.
它，作为我们的练习，我们会提出一个新的观点，
It, as our exercise, and
we'll make a new point,
我们将设置点y为未定义。
and we'll set point y to be undefined.
对，嗯哼，好的。
Right, mm-hm, okay.
我们再试一次。
We'll try it again.
差不多。
About the same.
对，有一种，它是一台电脑。
Right, there's a like, it's a computer.
有事情在做，事情在电脑上发生。
There are things doing,
things happening on the computer.
你的电脑可能比我的快，看数字略有不同。
Your computer might be faster than mine,
see slightly different numbers.
但总的来说，我们是在同一个球场上，对吧。
But generally speaking,
we're in the same ballpark, right.
好的，那很酷，当我们删除它时会发生什么？
Okay, that's cool,
what happens when we delete that?
我们将继续删除它，而不是将其设置为undefined。
Instead of setting it to undefined,
we'll go ahead and delete it.
差不多，好吧。
About the same, okay.
所以为什么我们可以删除它，我们可以将它设置为undefined。
So why we can delete it we
can set it to undefined.
看起来很有趣。
Seems pretty interesting.
那x呢？
What about x?
&gt；&gt；steve：所以这是未定义的。
&gt;&gt; Steve: So that's undefined.
好的，你看起来很棒，我一遍又一遍地看着同样的数字。
Okay you're like great I'm watching
the same numbers over and over again.
让我们继续删除x。
Let's go ahead and delete x.
&gt；&gt；steve：哇，&gt；&gt；steve：那个镜头。
&gt;&gt; Steve: Wow,
&gt;&gt; Steve: That shot up.
这很有趣对吧？
That's interesting right?
好吧。
Okay.
我们测量了一些东西。
We've measured something.
我们已经注意到这件事已经发生了。
We've noticed that thing has happened.
现在我们必须试着去处理它。
Now we have to try to deal with it.